Kingsley Solomon Ifijeh

Frontend Developer

Contact

Address

Ikorodu, Lagos (Open To Relocation), Nigeria 100001

Phone

+2348100792853

E-mail

kinxly@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kingsley-solomon-b9033

www

https://kingsley-solomon.vercel.app

Programming languages

Java

JavaScript (ES6)

HTMI

CSS/Scss

Libraries & Frameworks

React

Vue

Next.js

Nuxt.js

Bootstrap

Charkra UI

Vuetify

Skills

Communication

Problem Solving

Critical Thinking

Public Speaking

Active Listening

Collaboration

Innovative Web Developer with 5 years of experience in software development and Demonstrated talent for frontend web development to optimize online presence. A maestro in frameworks such as **React** and **Vue**, as well as scripting languages such as **JavaScript**.

Work History

2021-10 - Current

Frontend Engineer (contract)

ClapMi, Lagos

- Actively listened to customers' requests, confirming full understanding before addressing concerns.
- Created plans and communicated deadlines to complete projects on time.
- Created UX strategies, including detailed wireframes and mockups.
- Collaborated with team members to achieve target results.
- Translated UX and business requirements into elegant code solutions.

2021-09 - Current

Web Developer

Wewetube, Lagos, Nigeria

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve user
 problems.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Contributed to projects within Scrum project management environments.
- Transformed native applications into mobile-friendly products.

2020-07 - 2021-09

Front End Developer

Strategic Dots (TechStudio) Ltd, Lagos, Nigeria

- Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals.
- Performed user experience quality assurance testing to identify and remedy shortcomings
- Took part in pre-project analysis and technical evaluations to create user-friendly interface and appropriate functionality to achieve corporate objectives

2020-07 - 2021-09

Code Instructor

Strategic Dots (TechStudio Academy) Ltd, Lagos

- Teaching students basics of frontend development. i.e HTML, CSS Bootstrap and Javascript and React.
- Collaborated with students to complete homework assignments, identify lagging skills and correct weaknesses.
- Supported students with helpful study habits and strategies to reduce "code block" through critical thinking.
- Facilitated online Frontend development classes.

2021-02 - 2021-05

Web Developer (Contract)

Darex Engineering, Lagos

- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Actively listened to customers' requests, confirming full understanding before addressing concerns.

Education

2013-09 - 20170

Bachelor of Science: Industrial Chemistry

Bowen University - Osun, Nigeria

2006-09 -2009-10

High School Diploma

Kith And Kin International College - Lagos, Nigeria